<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Contract Specification on Belfry Projects</title><link>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/070-contract-specification/</link><description>Recent content in Contract Specification on Belfry Projects</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/070-contract-specification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Technical Options</title><link>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/070-contract-specification/technical-options/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/070-contract-specification/technical-options/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="contract-specification-technical-options">
 Contract Specification: Technical Options
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#contract-specification-technical-options">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>This Addendum supports the process of preparing a contract specification with descriptions of various parts of an installation which may be relevant to your tower. For those less familiar with bell installations, links are included to relevant chapters in the companion document &lt;a href="https://belfryupkeep.cccbr.org.uk">Belfry Upkeep&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Code of Practice on the Conservation and repair of bells and bell frames is available as a &lt;a href="https://www.churchofengland.org/sites/default/files/2018-11/CCB_Code-of-practice_Conservation-and-repair-of-bells-and-bellframes_2007.pdf">PDF download&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-tower">
 The Tower
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#the-tower">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For new bell installations and projects involving changes to the location of the bells, important considerations will be where and how the bells are to be (re)located in the tower. &lt;a href="../../115-specialists/#structural-engineers">Structural engineers&lt;/a> are likely to advise on the suitability and strength of the tower structure and its ability to accommodate the bells at the location intended. An architect may be engaged as well, particularly where alterations in the church are more extensive and design work will be required. The church architect should be informed of the work proposed, particularly any changes that will impact the visual appearance of the building internally or externally.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>