<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stakeholder Engagement on Belfry Projects</title><link>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/060-stakeholder-engagement/</link><description>Recent content in Stakeholder Engagement on Belfry Projects</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/060-stakeholder-engagement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ideas for Engagement</title><link>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/060-stakeholder-engagement/engagement-ideas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/060-stakeholder-engagement/engagement-ideas/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="ideas-for-stakeholder-engagement">
 Ideas for Stakeholder Engagement
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#ideas-for-stakeholder-engagement">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="general-points">
 General Points
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#general-points">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Consider how to reach out to different groups, particularly those not normally involved in church activities, using various aspect of the project that will be relevant to different groups.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The project launch will provide the stimulus for preparation of a set of materials that can be used subsequently at other events during the life of the project.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Prepare information using various formats for talks and presentations, displays, leaflets, podcasts, videos, sketches, diagrams, models, artefacts etc. Versions will need to be adjusted to suit different audiences and time available – consider young people and school children, neighbours and local residents, local organisations and companies, etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Design the information so that it will not need updating too frequently but make sure that it is kept up to date. Involve someone with artistic flair while making the information accurate and realistic, with a range of users in mind.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Early in a project, develop a style that will be used throughout. This may be based on an existing style used by the church but probably customised specifically for the bells project. Consistent use of colour and a logo help to reinforce the messages about the project, make it “eye catching” and memorable. Moderate use of colour and an “open” layout rather than dense typescript, aids readability. Pictures, diagrams, charts and tables all help readers to understand what is presented and feel that they wish to participate.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>With any information indicate how donations may be made to the project fund: bank details, address for cheques, or electronic links.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Invite people to become involved in the project and, maybe, learn to ring.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="what-to-include">
 What to Include
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#what-to-include">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The content will include key facts about the project, the current situation, the aims, timescales, what will be involved, the people involved, and why the project is needed. Most importantly, indicate the benefits for various stakeholders. Include plenty of pictures, links to videos, as well as technical details such as plans and designs for the proposed work. Show pictures of existing bells, perhaps with indications of current problems, then with examples to show what is envisaged. Indicate the costs of parts of the work to add some reality. Put the project in context for each stakeholder from their viewpoint – benefits, history, personal connections, facilities, landmark events. Look for ideas from similar projects elsewhere, but every project is unique so show it as such. Remember that people will want to see how the project relates to them as individuals.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>