<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docs on Belfry Projects</title><link>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Docs on Belfry Projects</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/010-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/010-introduction/</guid><description>Introduction # Bells are often heard but not seen! Ringing bells full circle is not just a church activity; it is part of our national heritage. A four hundred year old tradition, it offers challenges and requires skills which most people are able to achieve. Whilst it is based at the parish church and is a part of the worshipping Christian community, a band of ringers is part of the social life of the parish.</description></item><item><title>Scoping the Project</title><link>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/020-scoping-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/020-scoping-project/</guid><description>Scoping the Project # Of the over 7000 rings of bells in the world, around 90% are within the jurisdiction of the Church of England (CoE). We will use terms such as &amp;lsquo;incumbent&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;church wardens&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Parochial Church Council (PCC)&amp;rsquo; in this document. We trust you can translate these into the equivalent terms in other jurisdictions. A bell project may start as the seed of an idea or it may already have been discussed in a committee such as the Parochial Church Council (PCC).</description></item><item><title>Getting Specialist Advice</title><link>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/030-specialist-advice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/030-specialist-advice/</guid><description>UNDER CONSTRUCTION
Getting Specialist Advice # It is only with specialist advice that the full scale and scope of a project is likely to be determined. Every tower and ring of bells is unique so advice on the tower and bell installation will have to relate to each project specifically.
As with other major projects, many people will be concerned that they do not know where to start, where to obtain advice or even what advice will be needed.</description></item><item><title>Permissions &amp; Approvals</title><link>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/035-permissions-approvals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/035-permissions-approvals/</guid><description>Permissions &amp;amp; Approvals # UNDER CONSTRUCTION
Over 90% of the 7000 towers with 3 or more bells hung for full circle change ringing are in a Church of England Church, the remainder being owned by other churches, trusts, local authorities or privately whether in the UK or overseas. This means that bell ringers embarking on a bell project must act in conjunction with others who own and have responsibility for the tower and installation.</description></item><item><title>Managing the Project</title><link>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/040-managing-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/040-managing-project/</guid><description>Managing the Project # UNDER CONSTRUCTION
A plan to go from this… # Figure 1: Old timber frame at Hitcham, Suffolk
As a project takes shape there may be enthusiasm to make progress, particularly start raising money. However, it is advisable to plan the project, considering in some detail what has to be done when, how, by whom, with what resources first. The plan will ideally run from the earliest discussions through to project completion.</description></item><item><title>Project Team</title><link>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/050-project-team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/050-project-team/</guid><description>Project Team # UNDER CONSTRUCTION
A project may be proposed by one or two individuals with ambitions to achieve certain outcomes. However, it is usually better for a small group of people with a wider range of skills, interests and experiences to work together to make the project a success. It is advisable that the project is not the direct responsibility of an existing committee such as the PCC as that will usually have many other commitments and structured ways of operating; the team will need flexibility to plan the work and establish ways of working that will achieve the outcomes intended.</description></item><item><title>Project Finance</title><link>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/090-project-finance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/090-project-finance/</guid><description>Project Finance # UNDER CONSTRUCTION
“How much is required and how do we raise the money?” are often the first questions asked when a bell project is suggested. Most churches are short of money whether for routine expenses or for higher priority projects. However, bell projects usually attract donations and support from people who are not otherwise connected with the church, as well as from ringers and regular contributors. Donations may come from unexpected sources, unpredictably, often surprisingly quickly.</description></item><item><title>Regulations &amp; Compliance Matters</title><link>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/100-regulations-compliance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/100-regulations-compliance/</guid><description>Regulations &amp;amp; Compliance Matters # UNDER CONSTRUCTION
During a bell project, various regulations, standards, policies and practices will be encountered. Some of these will be managed by suppliers and contractors but ringers and tower authorities should be aware of the implications as failure to observe them can have serious repercussions. Requirements related to towers within the Church of England and other jurisdictions are given in a companion document and further requirements related to Health &amp;amp; Safety, Construction Design &amp;amp; Management and Insurance are covered below.</description></item><item><title>Project Completion</title><link>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/110-project-completion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/110-project-completion/</guid><description>Project Completion # UNDER CONSTRUCTION
After many months and often years of hard work, with disappointments and excitements on the way, the project will be completed successfully!
Resuming RInging # Since ringing will be resuming, it will be timely to alert neighbours of the completion of the work and advise them of likely ringing times for the regular services and practices. They are more likely to understand and be tolerant if they know in advance when ringing will occur, especially anything that is out of the ordinary.</description></item><item><title>Specialist Services</title><link>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/115-specialists/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://belfryprojects.cccbr.org.uk/docs/115-specialists/</guid><description>Specialist Services # UNDER CONSTRUCTION
These are names and web addresses (or telephone numbers if no website) of organisations providing specialist services for bell installations.
Note that the Central Council of Church Bell Ringers does not endorse or recommend specific companies. The information below is added to assist readers. Legitimate requests for amendments or additions may be requested through the Stewardship &amp;amp; Management Work Group Secretary at smSec@cccbr.org.uk. Bell Founders # Name Location Contact Fonderia Allanconi Bolzone, Province of Cremona, Italy http://allanconi.</description></item></channel></rss>